James Dugan papers, 1933-1977 00242
Eberly Family Special Collections Library
- Information Files, 5
  - Reviews, undated; 1 Items (Box 42)
  - Spindrift - PMM, undated; 1 Items (Box 42)
  - Marine Technology Society, undated; 1 Items (Box 43)
  - MAUC, undated; 1 Items (Box 43)
  - New Jersey Council, undated; 1 Items (Box 43)
  - New York Academy of Sciences, undated; 1 Items (Box 43)
  - New York Zoological Society - Aquarium, undated; 1 Items (Box 43)
  - Northeast Council, undated; 1 Items (Box 43)
  - Oceanic Research Associates, undated; 1 Items (Box 43)
  - Overseas Press Club, undated; 1 Items (Box 43)
  - Pacific Science Association, undated; 1 Items (Box 43)
  - Scipps Institute, undated; 1 Items (Box 43)
  - Sea Horse Institute, undated; 1 Items (Box 43)
  - Smithsonian Institution, undated; 1 Items (Box 43)
  - Society Hill Civic Organization, undated; 1 Items (Box 43)
  - Steamship History Society, undated; 1 Items (Box 43)
  - Trolley Museum, undated; 1 Items (Box 43)
  - Underwater Society of America I and II, undated; 2 Items (Box 43)
  - UNESCO - Marine Sciences Committee, undated; 1 Items (Box 43)
  - Woods Hole, undated; 1 Items (Box 43)
  - Writers Guild, undated; 1 Items (Box 43)
- Manuscript, 6
  - Men Under Water correspondence and layout materials, 1963-1966; 1 Items (Box 1)
  - Men Under Water Manuscript, 1965; 1 Items (Box 1)
  - Gavelord, Hause, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Goldstein, Bob, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Harrison, Rex; Palemer, Lilie, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Hotson, Leslie, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Kash, Jack, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Kaye, Danny, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Kelly, Walt, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Kieser, Roy, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Men, Ships and Sea, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Mohenjo-Daro, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Nautilus Album, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - New York Times Magainze, Book Reviews, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Ocean Roundup, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Paley, Wm, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Parades, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Pickford, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Ploesti - Section B Photo Narrative Action on Target, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Pocahontas, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Powell-Pressberger, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Scott, B.A., undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Slim, Gen. Sir Wm, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Slocum, Josh, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Spillane, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Sunken History, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Tait, Dean, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Three-Dimensional Yachting, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Top Secret Dive (Keeble), undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Treasure Fiction, undated; 1 Items; Moving Image--Film--16mm (Box 15)
  - Underwater Archaeology- NY Times, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Wallace, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Water, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Welitch, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - What's Going on Down There?, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - Williams, Art, undated; 1 Items (Box 15)
  - All About Ocean Riches, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Amphitrite, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Ancient Lights, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Aquarium, Coney Island, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Articles, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Atkinson, Art, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Atlantic City, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Avalanche, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Blowing Up at Malta, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Builder Book, Preface, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Cartoonists - Lincoln Humorist, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Club DeLamer, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Cousteau for Argosy, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Cousteau for Book of the Month Club News, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Cousteau for Holiday, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Cousteau for Sports Illustrated, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Department of Commerce, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Diving Encyclopedia Articles, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Farming Sea - London Tele, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Fashion Spy, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - First of Menfish, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Flying Enterprise Trip, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - French Club, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Grand Aurora, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Gulf Stream, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Hamo Aquatics (NY Times), undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Iceboat Fiction, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - International Geneva, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Inward Voyage - JYC, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - JYC Pieces, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - JYC Writings, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - King Joe, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Maquis Pieces, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Mr. Zeuss, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Ocean's Riches (All About), undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Understanding vs Technology - Reader's Digest, undated; 1 Items (Box 18)
  - Biographical Material, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Chaplin, Charles, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Coanda, Henri, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Cooke, Alastair, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Derry, John, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Dressler, Marie, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Dunning, Kathleen, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Edger, H.E., undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Effel, Jean, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Elliott Brothers, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Etches, Matilda, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Ferguson, Barbara, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Fisher, Hami, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Fontaine, Robert, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Franklin, Ben (Oceans), undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Giles, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Goldberg, Harris - Air Gunner, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Harington, Richard, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Ledyard, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Liebling, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Lillie, Bea, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Mayer, L.B., undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Nasmith, Submarine, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Scherman, Harry, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Simone, Cousteau, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Vumas, Frederick, undated; 1 Items (Box 24)
  - Cousteau - I and II, undated; 2 Items (Box 28)
  - GI's in London, undated; 1 Items (Box 42)
- Manuscript Research, 7
  - Bunk Johnson, undated; 1 Items (Box 4)
  - Capa, undated; 1 Items (Box 4)
  - James Mason, undated; 1 Items (Box 4)
  - Ploesti Notes, undated; 1 Items (Box 4)
  - Snoring, undated; 1 Items (Box 4)
  - Unfinished Manuscripts, undated; 1 Items (Box 4)
  - Chronology of Principle Events, 1942-1943; 1 Items (Box 5)
  - Calypso Notes, 1960; 1 Items (Box 6)
  - EIRE, undated; 1 Items (Box 6)
  - Silent World, 1960; 1 Items (Box 6)
  - Thirties, 1965; 1 Items (Box 6)
  - Chicago, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Hyde Park, 1962/03/27; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Joint Capital Improvements Program, 1962-1966; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Library Steps, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Monberg and Thorsen, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Report of Faculty Committee on Rental Polices, 1962/02; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - To Know New City Ask For Wise Men and Book, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Customs, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Feet, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Fenjohn, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Ferries, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Gl's In College, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Hamptons, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Housing, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Ice Boating, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Investing in Fisheries, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Lecture Biz, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Levittown, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Mascots, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Newsprint Data, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Nite Clubs, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Off-Schedule, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Round World Film, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Calypso - Press Release, undated; 1 Items (Box 29)
  - Cousteau Biographical, undated; 1 Items (Box 29)
  - Poisson Rouge, undated; 1 Items (Box 29)
  - Silent World Film Notices, undated; 1 Items (Box 30)
  - US Liason, undated; 1 Items (Box 30)
  - YANK - Army Weekly, 1945; 1 Items (Box 30)
  - Yugoslav Peoples Fight to Live, undated; 1 Items (Box 30)
  - Boston Sea Rovers, undated; 1 Items (Box 31)
  - Diving Patrol, undated; 1 Items (Box 31)
  - Diving Unions, undated; 1 Items (Box 31)
  - Filloux Expedition, undated; 1 Items (Box 31)
  - Undersea Technology, undated; 1 Items (Box 34)
  - Underwater Technics, Inc, undated; 1 Items (Box 34)
  - College Novel, undated; 1 Items (Box 35)
  - Lonergan Pieces, undated; 1 Items (Box 35)
  - New York Noise, undated; 1 Items (Box 35)
  - Notes - Ideas, undated; 1 Items (Box 35)
  - Story Ideas, undated; 1 Items (Box 35)
  - Wartime Pieces, undated; 1 Items (Box 35)
  - Aquarest - Cameron, undated; 1 Items (Box 40)
  - Dart Tagging, undated; 1 Items (Box 40)
  - Diving Publications, undated; 1 Items (Box 40)
  - Philadelphia Bulletin, undated; 1 Items (Box 40)
  - Gagnen and Razor, undated; 1 Items (Box 41)
  - Hamish Hamilton, undated; 1 Items (Box 41)
  - Bar Billiards, undated; 1 Items (Box 42)
  - Research Notes, undated; 1 Items (Box 42)
- Manuscripts & Proofs, 8
  - Adventures of Red Hat, 1936; 2 Items (Box 4)
  - Great Iron Ship, Author's Copy, undated; 1 Items (Box 4)
  - Great Iron Ship, Final Draft, undated; 1 Items (Box 4)
  - New Yorker Magazine, Letter to Editor, 1951/08/11; 2 Items (Box 4)
  - Old Main Bell, 1936; 1 Items (Box 4)
  - Ploesti Manuscript, undated; 1 Items (Box 4)
  - Short Comic Pieces, undated; 1 Items (Box 4)
  - Transactions, Calypso Oceanographic Expeditions, 1936; 1 Items (Box 4)
  - Ethiopia Controls/ Glossary, 1935-1936; 1 Items (Box 5)
  - Great Mutiny, undated; 1 Items (Box 5)
  - LIfe, Underwater Wonders, 1950/11/27; 1 Items (Box 5)
  - Living Sea Manuscript, 1963; 1 Items (Box 5)
  - Men Under Water Manuscript, undated; 1 Items (Box 5)
  - Underwater Treasury, undated; 1 Items (Box 5)
  - World Beneath Sea, 1967; 1 Items (Box 5)
  - Mutiny Under the Sea, undated; 1 Items (Box 6)
  - GIS Research and Letters, undated; 1 Items (Box 8)
  - Silent World, undated; 1 Items (Box 8)
  - Treasury, undated; 1 Items (Box 8)
  - Undersea Explorer, undated; 1 Items (Box 8)
  - Mutiny 1, undated; 1 Items (Box 9)
  - Ploest 1, undated; 1 Items (Box 9)
  - Albatross 9, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Architectural Forum - Magazine of Building, 1962/05; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Architectural Record, 1960/11; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Bright Block in Hyde Park, 1961; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Carlsen, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Chicago - Best of Everything, 1963/04/15; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Chicago - Where To Go and What To Do, 1963/04/27; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Chicago Daily News, 1963/11/09; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Chicago Scence, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Chicago Transit Map, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Chicago's American, 1961-1963; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Chinese War 11, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - City of Chicago Annual Report, 1962; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Conversion to Nuclear Propulsion, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Designs for Sixties, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Doria, Andrea, 1956; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Farm 7, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Flying Ships 10, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Get Ready for New Chicago, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Goodbye Greektown, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Hardstand 16, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Hunted Fleet 5, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Interreligious Understanding Through Art, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Little Wars 8, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Marine News, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Marooned 6, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Meet Your Amazing Chicago, 1958/03; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Midwest, 1963/04/28; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Pah-kwa or Eight Trigrams, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Peep 'O Day Boy 12, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Program for Community Improvement, 1961; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Shipping, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Silent World Film Gas and Oil, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Travel, 1956; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Voyage 17, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Whale Ship 4, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Youth 15, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Menfish, undated; 1 Items (Box 11)
  - Mutiny, undated; 1 Items (Box 11)
  - Bathyscaphe/DSL, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Canasta, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Chicago, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Comet, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Cunard Line, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Fishing & Sea Riches, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Free Diving Book of Knowledge, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Hudson's Bay Mining Notes, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Manuscripts and Proofs, undated; 1 Items (Box 30)
  - Russian Royalties, undated; 1 Items (Box 37)
- Personal, 9
  - Soviet Posters, undated; 2 Items; Graphic--Posters (Box 1)
  - Letters of Sympathy, 1967; 1 Items (Box 5)
  - Personal Letters, undated; 1 Items (Box 7)
  - Conference on Planning and Preparation for Retirement, 1959/09/29; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Daley, Richard Mayor Statement, 1962/03/02; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Membership of ELY Chapter of International Fraternity, 1961/03/23; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Notes, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Sperling, Jack I. Aiderman Biography, undated; 1 Items (Box 10)
  - Biographical Material, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Genealogy, undated; 1 Items (Box 13)
  - Slides, undated; 1 Items; Photographic--Slides--35mm (Box 19)
  - Scrapbook, 1943-1967; 1 Items; Scrapbooks (Box 25)
  - Scrapbook, Writings, 1943-1949; 1 Items; Scrapbooks (Box 27)
  - Appearances - Television and Other, undated; 1 Items (Box 28)
  - Financial Records, 1955-1960; 1 Items (Box 28)
  - Biographical Data, 1912-1967; 1 Items (Box 30)
  - Illustrated Magazine, 1943/07/17; 1 Items (Box 30)
  - Kijk Magazine, undated; 1 Items (Box 30)
  - Life Magzine, 1943/09/13; 1 Items (Box 30)
  - Paris Delivre Magazine, 1944; 1 Items (Box 30)
  - Salute Magazine, 1946-1948; 1 Items (Box 30)
  - VOIR Magazine, undated; 1 Items (Box 30)
  - Competitions, undated; 1 Items (Box 31)
  - Cousteau - Dugan Accounts, 1961-1969; 1 Items (Box 35)
  - Cancelled Checks and Receipts, 1950; 1 Items (Box 37)
  - Diary, 1948; 1 Items (Box 37)
  - Hicksville Bank Statements, 1952; 1 Items (Box 37)
  - Receipts, 1949; 1 Items (Box 37)
  - Tax Information, 1951-1952; 1 Items (Box 37)
  - Thurber, James from Life Costello's drawing, 1961; 1 Items (Box 37)
  - Bank Statements, Cancelled Checks and Rubber Stamps, 1946-1948; 1 Items (Box 38)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1954; 1 Items (Box 38)
  - Diaries, 1951-1955; 8 Items (Box 38)
  - Income Tax Information, 1953-1956; 3 Items (Box 38)
  - Biographical Data, undated; 1 Items (Box 40)
  - Christmas Cards - Collection, undated; 1 Items (Box 40)
  - Boston Sea Rovers Special Award - James Dugan, 1959; 1 Items (Box 42)
  - Personal Papers, undated; 1 Items (Box 42)
  - Reminisence - Early Dugan Family, undated; 1 Items (Box 42)
  - Sympathy Letters re: Death of Dugan (2), undated; 1 Items (Box 42)
  - Telegram re: Underwater City at Shab Rumi Reefs Sudan (framed), undated; 1 Items (Box 42)
  - Address Book, undated; 1 Items (Box 44)
  - Calendar, Appointment, 1958-1959; 1 Items (Box 44)
  - Calendar, Appointment, 1966; 1 Items (Box 44)
  - Christmas List, undated; 1 Items (Box 44)
  - Martin, Charles Cartoon Drawing, 1944; 1 Items (Box 44)
  - Notes, 1949-1956; 1 Items (Box 44)
  - Passport and Business Cards, 1964; 1 Items (Box 44)
  - Calendars, 1961-1962 1977; 1977 (Box 45)
  - Financial Ledgers, 1954-1958 (Box 45)
  - Photographs and Slides, undated; Photographic--Prints--Black and White (Box 45)
  - Photographs and Slides, undated; Photographic--Slides--35mm (Box 45)
- Photographs, 10
  - Great Eastern, undated; 4 Items; Cartographic--Maps (Box 1)
  - Portrait Proof Sheet, undated; 1 Items; Photographic (Box 1)
  - Great Eastern, undated; 5 Items (Box 12)
  - Great Mutiny, undated; 2 Items (Box 12)
  - Man Under Sea, undated; 1 Items (Box 12)
  - Photographs, undated; 1 Items (Box 36)
  - Photographs, undated; 1 Items (Box 37)
  - D-Day, undated; 1 Items (Box 42)
- General, 11
  - Flying Enterprise (reels 1, 2), undated; 1 Items; Moving Image--Film--16mm (Box AV1)